<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technical on clifpage</title><link>http://cliford.net/tags/technical/</link><description>Recent content in Technical on clifpage</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-in</language><managingEditor>reach@cliford.net (Cliford)</managingEditor><webMaster>reach@cliford.net (Cliford)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 13:56:53 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cliford.net/tags/technical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Joy of Side Quests</title><link>http://cliford.net/posts/side-quests/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:36:51 +0530</pubDate><author>reach@cliford.net (Cliford)</author><guid>http://cliford.net/posts/side-quests/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely someone who finds great joy in finishing every side quest in a game, this post unfortunately isn&amp;rsquo;t about video games. One of the most satisfying feelings in life is when you&amp;rsquo;re able to solve a problem that you have in life by yourself (and a bit of internet research, of course), be that repairing some tech, designing a CAD model that fits perfectly into some nook, or even just turning something off and on again.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Microcontrollers, Mathematics and a Merry Christmas</title><link>http://cliford.net/posts/microcontrollers-mathematics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 22:13:31 +0530</pubDate><author>reach@cliford.net (Cliford)</author><guid>http://cliford.net/posts/microcontrollers-mathematics/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="prelude"&gt;Prelude&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to put up some lights around the house for this year&amp;rsquo;s Christmas. As is my curse, I decided to whip up some fancy rainbow animations using a bunch of &lt;a href="https://googlethatforyou.com?q=WS2811%20led" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer "&gt;WS2811&lt;/a&gt; LEDs and a NodeMCU that I had lying around. (see: &lt;a href="http://cliford.net/projects/leaprgb/" rel=""&gt;LeapRGB&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s unique about these LEDs is that each one contains an IC; as such, it allows you to individually control each LED in the strip. A typical LED strip might have a power and a ground line and have the entire strip light up uniformly. Here, we have a power, ground and a data line that can be fed using a microcontroller.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>On GNU/Linux and Ricing</title><link>http://cliford.net/posts/gnulinux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 17:13:01 +0530</pubDate><author>reach@cliford.net (Cliford)</author><guid>http://cliford.net/posts/gnulinux/</guid><description>&lt;data id="id-1" data-raw&gt;&lt;/data&gt;
&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No blog of mine is complete without a rant (and/or flex) about GNU/Linux and my choice of distro (take a guess). An introduction to the terms mentioned here for any uninitiated (non-existent) readers:-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GNU/Linux&lt;/strong&gt; (popularly &lt;a href="https://www.gnu.org/gnu/why-gnu-linux.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer "&gt;and arguably&lt;/a&gt; known as Linux): An open-source operating system (which can be &lt;a href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer "&gt;free&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rice&lt;/strong&gt;: a swamp grass which is widely cultivated as a source of food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the essential information, we can get on to the story of how my experience with Linux led me to start a tech-repair empire by &lt;a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Did%20You%20Try%20Putting%20It%20In%20Rice%3F" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer "&gt;&amp;ldquo;putting it in rice&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. I was approximately 0.38 years old when I first laid eyes on a rice grain &amp;hellip;..&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Setting Up a Website</title><link>http://cliford.net/posts/setting-up-a-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 19:05:38 +0530</pubDate><author>reach@cliford.net (Cliford)</author><guid>http://cliford.net/posts/setting-up-a-website/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="evil-backstory"&gt;(Evil) Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I finally decided to buy myself a domain and put myself out there on the interwebs. This obviously isn&amp;rsquo;t my first presence on the internet (throwback to pre-affordable-internet days when I used to sit around scrolling on the sand as opposed to almighty machine learning overlord curated content).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="old-website"&gt;Old Website&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I even used to have a website before this one. Right around the time I created a GitHub, I managed to whip up a simple landing page for myself which has been available at &lt;a href="https://clifordjoshy.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer "&gt;clifordjoshy.github.io&lt;/a&gt; for the past three years. By the time this goes up, that site (that I&amp;rsquo;ll let you know took me a whole night to figure out the CSS for) would&amp;rsquo;ve been long buried in some Microsoft cache somewhere. As a remembrance of the website that&amp;rsquo;s been with me throughout my (villainous?) journey, I&amp;rsquo;ll leave here a screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>