<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on clifpage</title><link>http://cliford.net/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on clifpage</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-in</language><managingEditor>reach@cliford.net (Cliford)</managingEditor><webMaster>reach@cliford.net (Cliford)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 13:56:53 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cliford.net/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Joy of Side Quests</title><link>http://cliford.net/posts/side-quests/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:36:51 +0530</pubDate><author>reach@cliford.net (Cliford)</author><guid>http://cliford.net/posts/side-quests/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely someone who finds great joy in finishing every side quest in a game, this post unfortunately isn&amp;rsquo;t about video games. One of the most satisfying feelings in life is when you&amp;rsquo;re able to solve a problem that you have in life by yourself (and a bit of internet research, of course), be that repairing some tech, designing a CAD model that fits perfectly into some nook, or even just turning something off and on again.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Year of City Walks</title><link>http://cliford.net/posts/walk-walk-walk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 13:35:51 +0530</pubDate><author>reach@cliford.net (Cliford)</author><guid>http://cliford.net/posts/walk-walk-walk/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I started off this year with a bunch of goals. Not sure if this is just me slowly entering my quarter-life crisis, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to (re)discover hobbies, find out things about myself and just do some soul-searching in general. While I might&amp;rsquo;ve given up on a bunch of these (RIP the dusty guitar in the corner of my room), the one goal I can say that I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with has been one to travel. I believe I&amp;rsquo;ve been to more places this year than any other year of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cafes, Curries and Other Adulting Adventures</title><link>http://cliford.net/posts/adulting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 12:01:36 +0000</pubDate><author>reach@cliford.net (Cliford)</author><guid>http://cliford.net/posts/adulting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a good while since I&amp;rsquo;ve come back to this blog. It&amp;rsquo;s something I always think I should do, but I just never get around to doing it. I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to shake the feeling that I will come back here in ten years and look to this blog in nostalgia. So, I figure it&amp;rsquo;s good to document what this point in my life was like. Why that has to be on a public blog on the Internet, I cannot explain.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>College: Calicut, Coding and COVID</title><link>http://cliford.net/posts/college-retrospect/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 16:28:59 +0530</pubDate><author>reach@cliford.net (Cliford)</author><guid>http://cliford.net/posts/college-retrospect/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A week back, my undergrad college (&lt;a href="https://nitc.ac.in" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer "&gt;NITC&lt;/a&gt;) education came to an end. Though I spent around a half of it sitting at my desk at home staring at a screen, I&amp;rsquo;m still leaving the place with a bunch of fond memories, some great experiences and an itch to talk about all of it. Luckily, I have this blog which has patiently been waiting for me to come scream into the void again.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>