<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Create - Tag - clifpage</title><link>http://cliford.net/tags/create/</link><description>Create - Tag - clifpage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-in</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 22:13:31 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cliford.net/tags/create/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Microcontrollers, Mathematics and a Merry Christmas</title><link>http://cliford.net/posts/microcontrollers-mathematics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 22:13:31 +0530</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://cliford.net/posts/microcontrollers-mathematics/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="prelude">Prelude</h2>
<p>We decided to put up some lights around the house for this year&rsquo;s Christmas. As is my curse, I decided to whip up some fancy rainbow animations using a bunch of <a href="https://googlethatforyou.com?q=WS2811%20led" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">WS2811</a> LEDs and a NodeMCU that I had lying around. (see: <a href="/projects/leaprgb/" rel="">LeapRGB</a>)</p>
<p>What&rsquo;s unique about these LEDs is that each one contains an IC; as such, it allows you to individually control each LED in the strip. A typical LED strip might have a power and a ground line and have the entire strip light up uniformly. Here, we have a power, ground and a data line that can be fed using a microcontroller.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Setting Up a Website</title><link>http://cliford.net/posts/setting-up-a-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 19:05:38 +0530</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://cliford.net/posts/setting-up-a-website/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="evil-backstory">(Evil) Backstory</h2>
<p>So, I finally decided to buy myself a domain and put myself out there on the interwebs. This obviously isn&rsquo;t my first presence on the internet (throwback to pre-affordable-internet days when I used to sit around scrolling on the sand as opposed to almighty machine learning overlord curated content).</p>
<h3 id="old-website">Old Website</h3>
<p>I even used to have a website before this one. Right around the time I created a GitHub, I managed to whip up a simple landing page for myself which has been available at <a href="https://clifordjoshy.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">clifordjoshy.github.io</a> for the past three years. By the time this goes up, that site (that I&rsquo;ll let you know took me a whole night to figure out the CSS for) would&rsquo;ve been long buried in some Microsoft cache somewhere. As a remembrance of the website that&rsquo;s been with me throughout my (villainous?) journey, I&rsquo;ll leave here a screenshot.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>